<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Efficient Git on Efficient-git</title><link>https://dwtechs.github.io/efficient-git/</link><description>Recent content in Efficient Git on Efficient-git</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dwtechs.github.io/efficient-git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://dwtechs.github.io/efficient-git/gitflow/branches/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwtechs.github.io/efficient-git/gitflow/branches/</guid><description>master: For production releases. develop: For next release development. Available branch prefixes for developers : feature: For new feature to develop. release: When release cycle is over. Features ready to ship are kept here. Freeing develop branch for next cycle. bugfix: For new bug to fix. hotfix: For production bug to fix ASAP on master branch. refactor: To improve or update code and structure. doc: To improve or update developer documentation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dwtechs.github.io/efficient-git/gitflow/conventional-commits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dwtechs.github.io/efficient-git/gitflow/conventional-commits/</guid><description>Following those rules bring great advantages to a project :
Automatic CHANGELOGs. Automatic semantic version bump (based on the types of commits landed). Communicate the nature of changes to teammates, the public, and other stakeholders. Trigger build and publish processes. Make it easier for people to contribute to the project, by allowing them to explore a more structured commit history. The message is structured as follows:
&amp;lt;type&amp;gt;([optional scope]): &amp;lt;description&amp;gt; [optional body] [optional footer] Types They are based on the Angular convention and must be one of the following:</description></item></channel></rss>